<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prototypes on TCG Prototypes</title><link>https://tcgprototypes.com/tags/prototypes/</link><description>Recent content in Prototypes on TCG Prototypes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tcgprototypes.com/tags/prototypes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Takumi Akabane Signed Personal Collection</title><link>https://tcgprototypes.com/p/takumi-akabane-signed-personal-collection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tcgprototypes.com/p/takumi-akabane-signed-personal-collection/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://tcgprototypes.com/p/takumi-akabane-signed-personal-collection/staycalm.gif" alt="Featured image of post Takumi Akabane Signed Personal Collection" />&lt;h2 id="cgc-witnessed-akabane-signed-cards">CGC Witnessed Akabane Signed Cards
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>I have no plans to post everytime a new set of cards hits the market, but since this is the first time cards from &amp;ldquo;Akabane&amp;rsquo;s Personal Collection&amp;rdquo; have been signed by Akabane and witnessed by CGC, I believe it&amp;rsquo;s worth posting about.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="display: flex; gap: 10px;">
&lt;img src="images/6012622006.webp" alt="Charizard Signed Beta" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;img src="images/6012622063.webp" alt="Scyther Signed Beta" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;img src="images/6012622123.webp" alt="Abra Signed Beta" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>As you can see from the images above, a number of Beta Playtest &amp;amp; three Alpha Presentation cards have gone up for sale at Alt. These cards are graded in CGC&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Signature Series&amp;rdquo; which gives them a gold label and certifies that CGC witnessed the signature happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While we&amp;rsquo;ve seen a few people post their cards signed by Akabane online, this is the first time I have seen his signature as part of the &amp;ldquo;Signature Series&amp;rdquo; and not just &amp;ldquo;Authentic Autograph&amp;rdquo;. To me, this makes these the grail of all prototype cards in the Pokemon TCG. Cards from his collection and signed by the man himself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find the cards up for sale by visiting this link:
&lt;a class="link" href="https://app.alt.xyz/liquid-auctions?query=Akabane&amp;amp;sortBy=highest_price_first" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://app.alt.xyz/liquid-auctions?query=Akabane&amp;sortBy=highest_price_first&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the direct link to the Alpha Presentation Charizard if you&amp;rsquo;re just interested in seeing how high the price can go: &lt;a class="link" href="https://app.alt.xyz/liquid-auctions/select-listing?ids=55c75d61-58fc-4eaa-ac5e-72806ac0fd69" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://app.alt.xyz/liquid-auctions/select-listing?ids=55c75d61-58fc-4eaa-ac5e-72806ac0fd69&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I had disposable income, I&amp;rsquo;d probably be bidding on the Beta Playtest Scyther to complement my unsigned one. Good luck to all who are able to snag one of these while they last. To me, these are incredible pieces of Pokemon TCG history and I hope they all make it into the hands of real enthusiests.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Message me on Instagram &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.instagram.com/mattcollects64/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>@MattCollects64&lt;/a> to let me know your thoughts on these cards, and please let me know if you snag any for your collection. I love seeing people share their grails.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Summarizing All Major Versions</title><link>https://tcgprototypes.com/p/summarizing-all-major-versions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tcgprototypes.com/p/summarizing-all-major-versions/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://tcgprototypes.com/p/summarizing-all-major-versions/cover.webp" alt="Featured image of post Summarizing All Major Versions" />&lt;p>For now, I have no intention of going into the history of who released these cards to the public and how they were verified as authentic. This has already been covered by many people like CGC cards, but I could write a post in the future if needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="why-make-this-postsite">Why make this post/site?
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>There has been a lot of confusion in the community around the Pokemon pre-release cards lately, and even some cards being listed incorrectly on auction houses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to make a single post that explains every main category of the pre-release cards so I, and the community, know exactly what we are looking at when these cards pop up in future discussions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="disclaimers">Disclaimers
&lt;/h3>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The information in this post and on the site are based on what I&amp;rsquo;ve read from the authenticator (CGC), some of the auction houses selling the cards, instagram videos by GemMintPokemon, excellent discussions over at the EliteFourm, and discussions I&amp;rsquo;ve had with individuals via DMs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I do not represent anyone from the TCG or have insider information. Information in this article may be inaccurate and need to be corrected over time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You should do your own research and not make purchase decisions based on what I&amp;rsquo;ve assembled here. I am not responsible for your decisions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All photos of the cards on this page came from CGC&amp;rsquo;s scans. I claim no ownership of the photos. I did cleanup the photos and remove them from the slabs to make it easier to view them. This site is being published for informational purposes only. None of this is commercial or for profit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="alpha-prototype-1995">Alpha Prototype (1995)
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The Alpha Prototype cards were produced in 1995, and are currently the earliest forms of a real test/demo of what a Pokemon TCG could actually look like (excluding the two Seadra Proof of Concept cards since they were a one off).&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="display: flex; gap: 10px;">
&lt;img src="images/AlphaPrototype.webp" alt="Alpha Prototype - Front" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;img src="images/AlphaPrototype_R.webp" alt="Alpha Prototype - Back" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Set includes 26 Pokemon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Printed on thick card stock (apparently thicker than normal TCG cards)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Used flipped sprites from the GameBoy games for the Pokemon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Are black and white&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nothing on the back of the card.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="alpha-playtest-1996">Alpha Playtest (1996)
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The Alpha Playtest cards are much closer to what you are familiar with seeing from the Pokemon TCG. They feature art from Ken Sugimori and only include Pokemon and Trainer cards from the Base Set.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="display: flex; gap: 10px;">
&lt;img src="images/AlphaPlaytest.webp" alt="Alpha Playtest - Front" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;img src="images/AlphaPlaytest_R.webp" alt="Alpha Playtest - Back" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Set includes Base Set Pokemon and Trainer cards&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Printed on paper and then stuck to card stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Art is now illustrations by Ken Sugimori&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Artwork has no background (with the exception of Porygon)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cards are in color (background of card is a solid color)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back of the card has a low-res, but colored version of the Pocket Monsters back design.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="beta-playtest-1996">Beta Playtest (1996)
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The Beta Playtest cards are the first time we see cards from the Fossil and Jungle Sets; all 151 Pokemon make an appearance in this testing phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="display: flex; gap: 10px;">
&lt;img src="images/BetaPlaytest.webp" alt="Beta Playtest - Front" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;img src="images/BetaPlaytest_R.webp" alt="Beta Playtest - Back" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Set includes Trainer cards and all 151 Pokemon for the first time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Printed on paper and then stuck to card stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Illustration credit misspells Ken Sugimori&amp;rsquo;s name as &amp;ldquo;Sugimorori&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Artwork has no background&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cards are in color (background of card is a solid color)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back of the card has a low-res, but colored version of the Pocket Monsters back design.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some Pokedex numbers may be wrong. Charizard for example shows incorrectly as No.005.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="delta-playtest-1996">Delta Playtest (1996)
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The Delta Playtest cards appear to only represent the starter Pokemon and their evolutions. At this time, no other Delta Playtest Pokemon have surfaced.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="display: flex; gap: 10px;">
&lt;img src="images/DeltaPlaytest.webp" alt="Delta Playtest - Front" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;img src="images/DeltaPlaytest_R.webp" alt="Delta Playtest - Back" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Set includes only the starters and their evolutions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Printed on paper and then stuck to card stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Illustrations now by Mitsuhiro Arita and Ken Sugimori (spelled correctly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Illustrations represent what we see in the official launch.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Artwork has full character and background&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cards are in color (background of card is a solid color)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back of the card has a low-res, but colored version of the Pocket Monsters back design.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some Pokedex numbers may be wrong. Charizard for example shows incorrectly as No.005.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="alpha-presentation-1996">Alpha Presentation (1996)
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The Alpha Presentation cards appear to only represent a limited number of Pokemon: Venusaur, Charizard, Blastoise, Pikachu, Clefairy, Machoke, Porygon, Dragonite, and Mewtwo.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="display: flex; gap: 10px;">
&lt;img src="images/AlphaPresentation.webp" alt="Alpha Presentation - Front" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;img src="images/AlphaPresentation_R.webp" alt="Alpha Presentation - Back" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Set includes limited number of Pokemon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Printed on paper and then stuck to card stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Illustrations by Ken Sugimori&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Artwork has full character and background&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cards are in color (background of card is a solid color)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Energies finally have symbols in the attack area.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back of the card has a low-res, but colored version of the Pocket Monsters back design.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some Pokedex numbers may be wrong. Charizard for example shows incorrectly as No.005.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="beta-presentation-1996">Beta Presentation (1996)
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The Beta Presentation cards appear to be the rarest of all the pre-release cards and are believed to be the cards from the early previews of the Pokemon TCG in the Corocoro magazine.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="display: flex; gap: 10px;">
&lt;img src="images/BetaPresentation.webp" alt="Beta Presentation - Front" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;img src="images/BetaPresentation_R.webp" alt="Beta Presentation - Back" style="width: 48%;">
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Only three Pokemon are graded or known to exist publicly: 1 Charizard, 1 Clefairy, and 1 Mewtwo.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Printed on paper and then stuck to card stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Illustrations by Ken Sugimori&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Artwork has full character and background&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cards are no longer a single color and instead have a patterned background like you see on the officially released cards.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Energies also have symbols in the attack area.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There is no back on these cards. It is just solid white.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Everything looks clearer and more bold (including text).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Charizard&amp;rsquo;s Pokedex number is finally corrected to No.006&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap Up
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="a-work-in-progress">A Work in Progress
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The information around these cards could change, additional categories of the pre-release cards could surface, or more. I will try to keep this site updated as major information is released, but I will reiterate that you should do your own research and come to your own conclusions. I wanted a site that clearly outlined what I believe the current state of these cards looks like, but that does not mean I, or the community, are 100% accurate. I am not responsible for any actions you take.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="thanks--credits">Thanks / Credits
&lt;/h3>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Thank you to the EliteFourm for being so informative and collaborative over the last few months. The community there is wonderful and has really done an excellent job discussing these cards.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thank you to CGC for grading/authenticating these cards and providing a wealth of knowledge to the community.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thank you to all of those who spoke with me through DMs and helped me clear up any confusion I had on these cards.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="other-cardsvariants">Other Cards/Variants
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Other pre-release cards do exist along with slight variations within the main categories above. I may make a separate post explaining these in the future.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>